Samuel Wilson

- **(233)** 246460176 <u>sixtus99@gmail.com</u>
 - Upper West Region, Kaleo Wa,

SUMMARY

I am an ambitious and versatile young professional fervent about Africa. I work gallantly on the fringes of Education, Information Technology and social development. With specialized knowledge in Information Technology in Education, Entrepreneurship, and Project Management, I am passionate about using Technology as a force for good. I envision myself in a position where I can influence change by making an impact to promote development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

GIFEC/ITU, Ghana — DTC Training Facilitator June 2021

- ❖ Trained participants on IT essentials, IOT and ICT as tool for Entrepreneurship.
- Mentored participants on Digital Marketing.

Kaleo CIC, Kaleo — *Co- manager* March 2019 - PRESENT

- ❖ Supervise daily administration of the CIC.
- Mentor users of facility on Digital Marketing.

TECHNEG, Wa — Founder and Director March 2018 - PRESENT

- ❖ Trained 100 youth on introduction to IT.
- ❖ Trained 100 youth on Graphic Design.
- Mentored participants on Digital Marketing.

ST. DOMINIC R/C JHS, KALEO — Subject *Teacher* March 2018 – September 2020

❖ Taught ICT, Mathematics, and English at the JHS level

- organized mocks, quizzes and inter-schools' debates
- ❖ Assisted in preparing the School Plan and Implementation Programme (SPIP).

Eduosia D/A JHS, Central Region — National Service

September 2016 - August 2017.

- ❖ Taught ICT, Mathematics, and English at the JHS level
- Organized mocks, quizzes and inter-schools' debates.

Infant Jesus School, Twifo Praso — ICT Instructor

Feb 2013 - July 2016

- ❖ Taught ICT, Mathematics, and English at the JHS level
- organized mocks, quizzes and inter-schools' debates

EDUCATION

Akenten Appiah-Menka University of Skill Training and Entrepreneur Development (AAMUSTED), Kumasi, Ghana — Bsc. Information Technology Educ.

August 2020 - Present

Jackson College of Education, Kumasi, Ghana — *Diploma in Basic Education* January 2014 - November 2016

St. Teresa's Seminary, Amisano, Ghana — WASSCE

September, 2004 – May 2008

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

Registered Teachers license

RELEVANT SKILL

- Technical Skill: Computer Programing, Project management
- Soft Skills: Team work, Customer service, communication and Active listening

LANGUAGES

English Language

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Java, JavaScript, Python, C++ and PHP

REFEREES

Available upon request